2022 hasn't been a great year for gaming
and I feel like we probably say that
about every year but this year in
particular is bad for a unique reason 22
hasn't had any controversial launches
like the broken state of Fallout 76's
release or micro transactions in
Battlefront 2 but this year has game
developers seemingly attempting to
release games with solid structures
fixable issues and low content on launch
but then absolutely ignoring the game
for six months after that launch Armory
forger Battlefield 2042 Halo infinite
games that make me question whether
these Publishers just forgot to plan
beyond their games launch or whether
they just decided that one-fifth of the
content upon release should be enough to
keep the gamers bellies full until the
next one right AAA keeps falling short
so the gamer looks Elsewhere for their
late night distractions Indie Games
modded games maybe but one game one game
gets it right
foreign
[Music]
well three games built over 15 years ago
adjusted improved combined into one
single downloadable file that you can
grab for free and play on any PC with a
graphics card
foreign
anomaly a modic conjunction and overhaul
of stalker shadow of Chernobyl clear sky
and call of pripyat that aims to create
a deep challenging sandbox survival
experience that can be adjusted to your
exact preference of things like bullet
damage Trader costs enemy spawn chances
where you can select a difficulty
setting like I did and go for the ride
anomaly is immense over 100 hours of
gameplay are sitting here easily with
high replayability due to the dynamic
events missions and enemy encounters
that occur all over the zone different
factions you can choose from that play
in entirely separate ways with different
starting equipment and locations and a
library of mods are even better yet
handcraft mod packages to download and
tweak the experience to your liking
recently I downloaded a pack of bots for
anomaly from a Teensy little mod pack
called stalker gamma gamma is created by
a guy named grock in his community of
cheeky breekies and is actively
maintained adjusted added to depending
on what grok or Crocs Community votes
for this is anomaly on steroids my PC
set updating for two hours and once it
was done I witnessed the program I let
run rampant on my computer install over
320 individual mods to my stalker game
with a convenient program where I can
disable or change any mod to suit my
needs equipped with subsections tags and
a search bar to help me find mods to
change them out I ran the game once and
immediately had a performance issue well
here we go again mods lagging my game
what's new every now and then I would
just stutter nothing would cause it I
could be underground above ground in
Cordon maybe the great swamps and every
few seconds my game would
gameplay wonder if there's something
that could fix these
stutters
there is no way this works that is so
different from any modding experience
I've ever had in any game boom I was in
stalker gamma 320 mods on top of stalker
anomaly's gigantic overhaul already
running smoothly I was ready to start my
nightly Adventures deep into a new
version of the dark and depressing land
of post-apocalypse Ukraine
foreign
Sky faction I began my quest to survive
the most dangerous regions of the Zone
but to do that I'd need better armor
better skills better weapons better
pizza and the less you choose to run
with a more hostile or maybe
militaristic faction you'll be working
your way up slowly from plinking Bandits
with a Makarov hunting small game with
an over under or risking yeeding your
femur to the next rookie Village for
some weaker artifact out of the local
anomaly field this First Act of an
anomaly playthrough by itself is a game
worth of content and fun
hear it whoa
oh my gosh there were two of them
the early bit of hard difficulty is
where you have low ammo and few
medications in case of injury fleeing
most of the dangers you encounter it's a
treacherous Zone with Bandits zombies
mutants and radiation at every turn I
was consistently drunk on vodka in my
first playthrough to sway radiation
poisoning as my uniform and gas masks
were futile against the clouds of
radioactive dust I was commonly out of
bandages meaning one scratch could mean
certain death and it's not an unfair
difficulty it might sound like it but
you can and will be able to eventually
catch a lucky break find a body with a
rifle that actually is fixable at the
workbench and feel that massive level of
accomplishment as you finally down
another human with a single shot it's
also the moments in between firefights
though that feel so alive in this game
and are so entertaining it's the moments
where it's 4 am I'm still playing
stalker and I'm sitting on the side of a
destroyed building just watching a
sunrise while faint gunshots and
occasional mutants Howl in the distance
the world is fully single player yet so
many things happen in it that don't rely
on player input at all they aren't even
designed to be within the player's
perception range either firefights can
be barely audible across the map and I
rarely ever know what the context is
behind a distant shot and I have the
option to go interact with these
unscripted events but I'll be risking my
stalker's life against other stalkers
and mutants who are equally as likely to
get one-shotted by a double barrel as I
am here I feel like I'm just another
stalker with matching abilities to one
walking out of the safe zone right in
front of me to go do a patrol this is
the exact chance I get to dig at Ghost
Recon breakpoint once again so of course
I have to
wow it just spawned the enemies right
beside the friendlies watch them fight
each other
look at this intense firefight
look how am I I'm terrified right now
I am so scared of what could potentially
happen to any of these guys
I mean I mean what what's gonna happen
to him you know are they gonna
oh there goes one you know guns don't
feel powerful
whenever you see
two groups of people fighting right with
guns about 10 feet away from each other
spraying mags upon mags upon mags of
ammo at each other and not killing each
other immediately how does that make me
feel as the player whenever I shoot
someone and they die immediately does
that make me feel like I'm part of the
world or like I am separate like I'm
cheating in the world if the AI aren't
dangerous on either side because they
can't even kill each other in 30 seconds
how does that make me feel when I'm
fighting the AI in this world you just
aren't a person in breakpoint you're a
God among idiots and stalker you see
people die from one hit you see just how
mortal humans are you shoot someone and
hear them crying as their lungs collapse
or cursing you as they die
foreign
[Music]
you see fellow stalkers discover a body
and Report the dead stalker on the
public chat system and then you see
other stalkers reply with their
condolences by seeing how quickly and
how often Others May die it makes every
movement every fight every evasion so
much more meaningful for once I feel
mortal in a single player game not just
because I can die but because I can die
just as easily and as quickly as anyone
else here so in which game do I feel
more alive the survival features in
breakpoint where you can do stuff like
drink water clean your weapons or
scratch down some notes for improved
stats or heavily advertised as a selling
point for the game but are never
required they're optional they don't
even punish you if you ignore them not
drinking water no negative effect of
course it's not a hardcore survival game
but I'll wrap up why I'm saying this in
a second in stalker anomaly you drink
water because it's required you eat
because it's required you get tired and
have to sleep because if you don't you
will get so tired that you won't be able
to walk you must balance your petty
Ernie things from Fetch quests and
mutant nuns to decide whether you want
more vodka to protect you from radiation
or more food to eat to keep your stalker
fast and energized survival is a
requirement
one game was advertised as a tactical
shooter with Survival game elements but
I'm very sure the devs were forced to
reverse the depth of their new survival
system to appeal to a wider audience and
net more sales the output is a weird
offhand throw at survival that feels
half-baked and neutered this mod is a
survival game with hundreds of different
developers coming together with
motivation to create a truly immersive
survival experience without the looming
fear of not appealing to a wide audience
also there's a mod in here called beefs
and vgs and they are the best nvgs of
any video game I've probably ever seen
oh
look at that looks pretty good look at
the outside and then the sparkle the
grain yep so this is this is a pbs7 I
don't know some Russian dual tubes
look at the blur too
it's actually that's really good let's
close
isn't that awesome and then the outside
of the night vision is color and then uh
let me try the quad knots
oh there's quads oh my God
damn that looks good I love the fact
that there's actually color outside of
the tube dude wow as you get a bit
deeper in your playthrough find yourself
a modern weapon obtain a better
equipment to allow yourself into more
dangerous zones you'll find yourself
getting into a rhythm with the game are
you commonly searching for artifacts are
you hunting mutants do you cook your own
food or make do with what the Traders
sell are you heavily combat oriented or
preferred to save money on meds and ammo
by avoiding most of those fights these
are questions you will answer in your
playthrough that will shape your stalker
over time as different pieces of
equipment clothing medications weapons
and ammo types will decide on what style
of gameplay you'll be effective at and
your carrying capacity will not allow
you to carry one of everything until
you're way far in an exosuit and for
reference I'm 25 hours into a
playthrough right now and just fully
repaired a pp19 bison to become my first
functional full auto weapon until then I
was running a Mosin in USP for most the
time crying when anything got closer
than 10 feet
foreign
God Jesus
[ __ ] he's back up
[Music]
foreign
it's a small one too
up like halfway up a ladder
[ __ ] yeah I hate those things too
eventually you'll reach a high enough
reputation with traders that you can buy
better parts and ammo for higher end
weapons and enemies will eventually
spawn with better weapons and gear too
once you drop them and loot their bodies
meaning at some point you'll be able to
progress all the way to a powered
exoskeleton suit and high-end tarkov
like weaponry and I just appreciate that
depth in all chapters of the game from
beginning poor to becoming a high-end
legend in the zone the game throws
logistical curveballs at you and still
surprises you to slow your progression
down to a speed at which you can savor
it switching off of a Mosin Nagant after
days of playing with it was tough It's
been with me for weeks of a playthrough
but I was finally moving on to something
bigger other sections of the experience
have depth due to the already large lore
base of the stalker universe meaning the
Zone can throw a bloodsucker a squad of
heavily geared monolith soldiers Bandits
or a pack of dogs at you from the same
spawn point all with different required
reactions from the player to deal with
safely and similar to other games we
play here on the channel this game is a
massive sandbox with many ways to play
gather your buddies on Discord new
playthrough the player is forced to do
nothing but hunt artifacts take a drink
or shot a vodka when your stalker has to
drink Vodka to negate radiation
poisoning fun ensues all right here we
go well this one I'm not a huge fan of
oh I got I'm stuck
I have to reload because it's not really
that much no problem in the future can
you eat the anomalous bread though
I don't know if that's such a good idea
24 millisieverts an hour can you digest
the radiation your poo would be glowing
green bro you get killed by a
bloodsucker or you die of green poo I'm
gonna pick the green poo every time oh
you're uh resistance just everything by
it is
sipping all right here we go
it's a new Mutant that got added by this
mod and it's basically sounds like a
piranha sounds like a motorboat yeah
basically what it is what it is it's
simple I just want to hear the piranha
sounds like raw in my ear just dude
he's got seven artifacts on him Josh
that's you you idiot
dude this is literally me no he turns
around him
you're putting stuff off shots
did you not notice that's what I meant
it's you touched him out
that's a drink water moment
oh yeah oh there's some hardships I am
dude you're walking into it dude I don't
have any balls you don't have bolts
oh that goes crazy super fast fighter
right right fire of rate
how are you
there's more modes than one as well a
fun one in the game is the Iron Man mode
where your save will delete itself after
you run out of a pre-selected amount of
lives or another mode where when you die
you enter the body of another AI stalker
in the zone and play on as that stalker
it's a game that's filled with a Sandbox
of settings and tools to tweak and play
with to your heart's content seriously
imagine I really want you to imagine a
new single player Survival game dropping
today from some company or any company
for sixty dollars with the same level of
depth customization and replayability as
this experience IGN would be giving this
10 out of 10s across the board for its
impressive and unique visuals and high
amount of content immersive environment
sound systems Etc and it have the
biggest streamers hooked on it for
months Instead This is an old game that
was originally one with Big Ideas
limited by the era it was born in left
to be played by only few because of the
Prejudice of unaware gamers thinking of
it as old or clunky when in reality the
gameplay of stalker gamma and stalker
anomaly competes with modern day games
so closely because it's been tuned and
adjusted by a crowd-sourced effort for
years much more powerful than any AAA
game Studio this is what you get when
you have people who are actually making
a game based on what they think is cool
versus a game that's made for profit so
if you hear a friend mention that the
gaming landscape is dry right now going
to play a modded stalker experience
isn't just a rewind back for nostalgia's
sake it's a refresh of a formula that's
worked for years and being one of the
top survival experiences in gaming and
if you even want to go deeper stalker
gamma's pack adds a bunch more hardcore
fun to it too so pop a cold one spend a
lonely night in the game it'll make you
jump it'll make you frustrated
but it is undeniably an extreme amount
of value for the price of well nothing
or maybe your spicy internet bill after
downloading 350 mods
[Music]